# Rajinder Pal

**Mobile No:** +91-8872668838, 8146238168 (Punjab, India).

Email: -rajwinder.kohli27@gmail.com

Skype ID: - rajinder.pal1987

Address: - VPO - Bhanupali, Tehsil:-Nangal, District: - Rupnagar,

Punjab (INDIA) 140133

#### **Skills:-**

Transport Professional with over Five years of internationals experience in Transport, Vehicle Maintenance & Administration. Versatile, bilingual professional with management experience ranging in size from small private projects to full scale multi-million dollar high profile corporate Transportation projects. Ability to oversee and manage hundreds of individuals while ensuring timely completion of project deadlines all while remaining on or under budget. I am a graduate from Kurukshtra University and good computer skills.

### **Educational Qualification:-**

- Matriculation from Haryana Board, Bhiwani. (Haryana) (India)
- 10+2 from Haryana Board, Bhiwani. (Haryana) (India)
- Graduation from Kurukshtra University, Kurukshtra (Haryana) (India)

## **Work History:-**

## **International Experience:-**

1	Site Transport & Workshop	M/S Jambo Transporte, Demonic
	In- charge	Republic Congo, East Africa
2	Site Transport & Workshop	M/S Marmul Contraction &
	Supervisor	Engg L.L.C Muscat, Oman
3	Transport Analyst	Supreme Food Service,
		Afghanistan
4	H.R. Coordinator	Dubai Nova Constructions
		&Engg. L.L.C, Dubai, UAE.

## **Indian Experience:**

1	Computer Operator	Election Commission of India, Nawanshahr office (Punjab) India
2	Computer Operator	Canteen Store Department (Ministry of Defense) India.

## **Brief Employment History:**

#### 1. Site Transport & Workshop In-charge

Jambo Transporte, Demonic Republic Congo, East Africa, Aug 2015 to May 2016.

- In charge of the day to day operations of the transport department.
- Efficiently managing a team of drivers, Operators and Mechanics vehicles.
- Responsible for all of the dispatching, routing, and tracking of delivery vehicles.
- Ensuring company compliance of all transport policies, legislation and procedures.
- Managing, monitoring and developing a team of drivers and Mechanics.
- Involved in strategic development and strategy making.
- Making sure that all transport fleet vehicles are properly maintained and serviced.
- Arranging for the induction and training off all new staff.
- Developing and nurturing customer relationships.
- Maintaining accurate administrative records.
- Organizing vehicle checks, Identifying operational issues, potential problems and opportunities.
- Resolving and managing queries and complaints courteously and efficiently.
- Appraising staff performance and also taking disciplinary measures when required.
- Ensuring all site and customer objectives are achieved.

## 2. <u>Site Transport & Workshop Supervisor:-</u>

M/S Marmul Contraction & Engg L.L.C Muscat, Oman Jan 2015 to April 2015.

- To ensure the efficient and effective use of staff, workshop/body-shop facilities and equipment.
- To determine priorities and allocate work to workshop/body-shop staff.
- To ensure service and repair targets are met.
- To liaise with the Plant Manager on issues affecting availability of parts, and to take responsibility for parts.
- To communicate with external repair agencies as necessary.

- Efficiently managing a team of drivers and vehicles. Responsible for all of the dispatching, routing, and tracking of delivery vehicles.
- Ensuring company compliance of all transport policies, legislation and procedures to do.
- Being the first point of contact for all drivers.
- Making sure that all transport fleet vehicles are properly maintained and serviced.
- Organizing vehicle checks, Identifying operational issues, potential problems and opportunities.
- Resolving and managing queries and complaints courteously and efficiently.

#### 3. Transport Analyst: -

Supreme Logistics, Kabul, Afghanistan-July 2010 to May 2012.

- Approving Time sheets for delivery
- Signing payment vouchers
- Monitoring Cargo Movement through tracking system
- Issuing fuel cards to drivers
- Developing new duty rosters for drivers
- Scheduling maintenance charts for all vehicles
- Preparing daily vehicle movements reports
- Preparing daily Schedule for dry/ frozen and chillers Trucks
- Preparing daily truck dispatch checklist
- Analyze the reports through COMS & WMS
- Analyze the Transporter Invoices Before processing for payment.
- Payments to Transporters working for Supreme Food Service Afghanistan
- Preparing PO & Payment Vouchers of Transporters Invoices and Approval.
- Maintaining the record of Transporters billing
- Reconcile and analyze the data received from Dispatch team with transporters Invoices
- Point of contact for Transporters Billing queries.
- Follow up with Finance manager for monthly billing to customer & preparing report for central Finance.
- Handle the outbound and Inbound billing data
- Handle the outgoing and incoming correspondence of Finance department of transport related.

#### **4.** H.R. Coordinator: -

Dubai Nova Constructions & Engg. Co. L.L.C, Dubai, UAE Oct 2007 to Dec. 2009.

- Maintains Department office area in an organized and professional manner.
- Coordinates activities, information meetings, and various training programs.
- Implements and maintains filing system, both paper and computer.
- Provides administrative support in the preparation of correspondence, reports, schedules, confidential materials and various employee issues
- Answers the telephone in a professional manner and assists internal guests with any questions, directions to the property, etc
- Assists candidates to post their resume on line.
- Assists the HR Director with the recruitment, interviewing, and selection processes and sends appropriate correspondence to all applicants in a timely manner.
- Maintains a daily log of important information to share with the department
- Support the department implementing training and development programs to ensure optimal company-wide performance
- Plans and assists conducting monthly new hire orientation programs
- Assists in development of new programs and services as they relate to Human Resources.
- Assists in development of Personnel Policies and Procedures
- Assists in implementing changes to effect continual improvement in services provided; and complies with regulatory and legal requirements.
- Processing Visas & Visa Cancellation, Absconder Declaration.
- Processing Travel documents (Tickets, Hotel Booking & Visas)
- Maintaining the personal files of 13000 workers
- Preparing payroll and benefits of 13000 workers
- Handle the complaints of workers and client companies

### **5.** Computer Operator:-

Election commission of India,  $7^{\rm th}\,January~2006$  to October 2007.

- Making voter card of every voters in Nawanshahr District in behalf of Election Commission of India.
- Preparing the voter sheet of the Nawanshahr district.
- Keeping the record of voter sheet every month.

- Amendment of currant voter rolls like addition & subtraction of voters
- Upload the data at the time of voting held in Nawanshar district in election commission official website.

#### **6.** Computer Operator:-

Canteen Store Department (Ministry of Defense India), Dec. 2001 to Aug.2005.

- Generating invoices through the specific software modified by the Department of vehicle sold by Canteen store department to the army personals.
- Collating the monthly report of sold items.
- Maintenance of computers & software of the CSD.
- Reconcile the data with the accounts department and the suppliers.
- Checking the forms of request received from the army personal for the vehicle & other house hold items prior to delivery of items.
- Communicate with all army personal for their quarries.
- Preparing the rates and index no of all the items sold by CSD depot Ambala.
- Maintain the record of sold items request forms day by day.

## **Professional Qualification:-**

- One year Software Diploma from Star computer, Ambala Cantt, (Haryana) India.
- One year advance Software Diploma from Haryana State elect.
   Development Co-op Chandigarh. (Haryana) India.

### Personal information: -

Place of Birth : Anandpur Sahib (Punjab)

Date of Birth : June07, 1979.

Marital Status : Married
Father's Name : Ram Kishan
Passport No : P0860537

Religion : Hindu

Language : Hindi, English, Sawayli(French) & Punjabi

#### **References:-**

1.) Steve Sutcliff

General Manager - Security

Supreme Logistics

steve.sutcliffe@supreme-group.net

2.) Nigel Emms

Operations Manager- Convoy Planning

Supreme Logistics

nigel.emms@supreme-group.net

3.) David Allison

Convoy Planning (Compliance)

Supreme Group

david.allison@supreme-group.net

+ 93- 785832403

4.) Harish Joshi

Sr. Plant Manager

Marmul Contracting & Engg Co Oman

+968-91394288-Oman

+91-9997666504-India

5.) Mr. Paul Krishanmoorthy

**Transport Director** 

Jambo Transporte, DRC

+243-976968384

+243-998610122

I hereby certify that all of the above information are true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Place: - Nangal

Rajinder Pal Applicant's signature Dam (India)